《异形3》
Stasis interrupted。Fire in cryogenic compartment.
静态平衡受到干扰，低温舱发生火警
Repeat。Fire in cryogenic compartment.
重覆，低温舱发生火警
All personnel report to…
所有人员速到…
emergency escape vehicle.
紧急逃生小艇发射台报到
Launch of the escape lifeboat will commence…
太空飞行将在…
in T-minus 20 seconds.
20秒后开始
（费欧娜「复仇」161星 外围矿沙提炼厂）
（双Y染色体 劳改监狱）
（最高设防监狱）
An E.E.V.'s come down.
一艘逃生艇坠落
Get down to the beach。There may be others.
到沙滩去，可能还有其他人
Now！
快去！
Talk to me.
说说话
Come on。Come on.
快醒醒！快醒醒！
Hey，Frank！Come on！Let's go！Let's go！
嘿！弗兰克！快！走了！
Wait！
等等！
（费欧娜161C级监狱 报告逃生小艇2650坠落）
（蕾普莉中尉：生还者）
（希克斯下士：死亡）
（身份不明女性：死亡）
（约10岁）
（要求最迅速紧急救援）
（等候回应 狱长安德鲁斯）
Get goin'，Frank。Get in there.
弗兰克，进去看看
Oh！Jesus Christ！
天啊！
Hell of a way to make a landing！
着陆真猛！
Use the torch.
用手电筒
- How many？- Don't know.
- 有多少？- 不知道
Three。Maybe four.
3个，也许4个
Hey，Frank。Can we hurry this up？It's gonna be 40 below in five minutes.
嘿，弗兰克，速度起来，5分钟后就零下40度
（致费欧娜161C级监狱）
（通讯卫星通报：伟伦优达尼公司收到报告）
All right，all right。Let's get it going.
好了，大家集合
Keep it together。Come on。Right.
集合了，快点
Right。Here we go，Mr。Dillon.
可以了，迪伦先生
Give us strength，O Lord，to endure.
主呀，给我们力量来坚守
We recognize that we are poor sinners in the hands of an angry God.
我们只是上帝手中卑微的罪人
Let the circle be unbroken…
请以手包围我们…
until the day.
守护我们
- Amen。- Amen.
- 阿门 - 阿门
Thank you，gentlemen。This is rumor control.
谢谢各位，这是谣言管制会议
Here are the facts.
以下是案情
As some of you know，
你们也知道
a 337 model E.E.V…
一架337型号紧急逃生艇…
crash-landed here at 0600…
在早上六点…
on the morning watch.
坠落此地
There was one survivor，
上面有一名生还者
two dead and a droid that was hopelessly smashed beyond repair.
两具尸体，以及损毁得无法维修的生化人
The survivor is a woman.
生还者是个女人
That's what I saw.
漂亮吗？
I just want to say that I've taken a vow of celibacy.
我想说我已经发誓，要终生禁欲
- So have we all。- That also includes women.
- 我们都发誓过 - 包括对女人在内
- Yes。- We've all taken the vow！
- 是的 - 我们全都发过誓
- Shut your gob，Morse。- I'd like to say that I，for one，
- 闭上你的臭嘴 - 我要说的第一点
do not appreciate company policy allowing her to freely…
我不喜欢公司政策…
intermingle with inmates and the rest of the staff.
让她和囚犯及狱卒混在一起
What brother means to say is we view the presence of any outsider，
这位兄弟想说的是任何外人
especially a woman，as a violation of the harmony，
尤其是一个女人，都会破坏这里
a potential break in the spiritual unity.
和谐统一的精神
We are well aware of your feelings in this matter.
我们知道，大家的想法
You will be pleased to know that I have requested a rescue team.
我已申请救援小组前来
Hopefully，they will be here inside of a week-
若无阻碍，一周内将到达
Oh，come on！and evacuate her A.S.A.P.
然后尽快将她带离此地
Don't give us that！
少来这一套！
What's her medical status？
她的身体状况如何？
She doesn't seem too badly damaged.
伤势不重
She's unconscious。Can't give you a more specific diagnosis at the moment.
目前昏迷中，未能做更精确诊断
- Will she live？- I would think so.
- 她能活下来吗？- 我想应该会
Look。It's in everybody's interest…
大家都不希望…
the woman doesn't come out of the infirmary until the rescue team arrives.
那女人在救援小组到达前离开医疗室
- And certainly not without an escort，right？- Sir.
- 没人伴随更不可以，对吗？- 是
Gentlemen，we should all stick to our set routine…
各位，我们必须坚守日常生活…
and not get unduly agitated.
不要过度激动
Right。Correct？
对吧？
All right。Thank you，gentlemen.
很好，谢谢大家
All right.
好了
Better get here soon or there ain't gonna be much left.
他们最好早点到，否则她就死定了
What's that？
那是什么？
It's just a little cocktail of my own mix。Sort of eye-opener.
我自己调的鸡尾酒，给你前所未有的感受
You a doctor？
你是医生？
My name is Clemens。I'm the chief medical officer here.
我叫克莱门斯，这里的医疗主任
- Here？- Fury 161.
- 这里？- 复仇161星
It's one of Weyland-Yutani's backwater work prisons，
银河系最偏远的劳动监狱
it grieves me to say.
一提起就令我伤心
Do you mind？
别紧张
This is basically a stabilizer.
这东西是镇静剂
I really ought to shave your head.
我得剃掉你的头发
We have a big problem with lice here.
这里的头虱很多
And when you're feeling better，I'll give you some clippers，
等你感觉好点，我帮你剪发
- and you can tend to your private parts yourself。- How'd I get here？
- 你自己剪耻毛 - 我是怎么来的？
You crash-landed in an E.E.V.
你乘坐的逃生艇坠毁
Evidently separated from your mother ship before you hit our atmosphere.
进入大气层前才脱离你的母船
You have any idea how long you were in hypersleep？
知道你长眠多久吗？
'Cause coming out the way you did can be quite a jolt to the system.
你突然苏醒，可能对身体有影响
- Yeah，I'll be sick for a couple of weeks。- Indeed.
- 我会病几个星期 - 没错
- Where are the others？- They didn't make it.
- 其他人呢？- 全死了
- What？- They didn't survive.
- 什么？- 无一幸存
I have to get to the ship.
我要到船上
- Have to get to the ship。- You're in no condition for that.
- 我要到船上 - 你现在还不能去
You want to get me some clothes，or should I just go like this？
给我穿衣服，还是你要我这样出去？
Given the nature of our indigenous population，I would suggest clothes.
考虑到本地居民的性情，我建议你穿衣服
None of them have seen a woman in years.
他们好久没见过女色
Neither have I，for that matter.
我也一样
This used to be a 5，000 convict facility，
这里曾经收容五千名囚犯
but it's been reduced to a custodial staff of 25.
现在却只有25名
Why？
为什么？
- Keep the pilot light on。- The pilot light for what？
- 保持火焰不熄 - 什么火焰？
Blast furnace。Natural methane.
封闭式熔炉，天然沼气
We have a foundry，Lieutenant Ripley.
我们有个铸造厂，蕾普莉中尉
The inmates forge lead sheets for toxic waste containers.
囚犯打造铅片，围堵有毒废物
How do you know my name？
你怎么知道我的名字？
It's stenciled on the back of your shorts.
就写在你短裤背面
Release the cable！
把铁缆松开！
- Where are the bodies？- We have a morgue.
- 尸体在哪里？- 在殓房
We put them there until the investigative team arrives in about a week，I think.
调查小组一个星期后到达
- There was a droid。- Disconnected.
- 有一名生化人 - 残缺不全
There were bits and pieces of him all over the place.
到处都是碎片
We put what was left on the rubbish tip.
我们把残骸丢到垃圾场
The corporal was impaled by that safety support.
那名下士被安全支架刺死
He never knew what hit him.
死得不明不白
And the girl？
那个女孩呢？
She drowned in her cryo-tube.
她…溺死在低温舱内
I don't think she was conscious when it happened.
我想她没有知觉…当她死去时
Um，I'm sorry.
很抱歉
What's the matter？
怎么了？
- Where is she？- In the morgue.
- 她在哪里？- 在停尸间
I have to see her.
我要看她
I have to see what's left of her.
我要看看她的遗体
Is there any particular reason that you're so insistent？
为何你这么坚持？
Yes。I have to be sure how she died.
对，我要确定她的死因
I hate to be repetitious about such a sensitive subject，
对这种事情实在不必罗唆
but it is persectly clear that she drowned.
但她很明显是溺死的
Was she your daughter？
她是你女儿吗？
No。She wasn't.
不，她不是
C-Could I have a moment alone，please？
让我独处一下，好吗？
Yes，of course.
当然可以
Forgive me.
原谅我
What's she doing？
她在干嘛？
Okay？
你没事吧？
No.
没事
We have to do an autopsy.
我们得验尸
- What？- I told you，
- 什么？- 我说过了
we have to make sure how she died.
我们得查清楚她的死因
And I told you，she drowned.
我说过，她是溺死的
I'm not so sure。I-I have to see inside of her.
我不敢肯定，我们得看看她的体内
You're disorientated。Half your system's still in-
你精神恍惚
I have a very，very good reason.
我有很好的理由
Well，perhaps you'd like to share that reason.
那就请你把理由告诉我
Possible contagion.
她很可能受到感染
What kind exactly？
哪种感染？
- Cholera。- Cholera？
- 霍乱 - 霍乱？
There hasn't been a case of cholera reported for 200 years.
两百年来，一宗霍乱病例都没有
Please.
求求你
Everything's in place.
一切正常
There's no sign of infection.
没有感染的迹象
- No indication of disease。- Chest.
- 没有疾病的征状 - 胸腔
Open the chest.
打开胸腔
Careful.
小心点
Lungs.
肺部
Flooded with fluid.
充满液体
Ergo，she drowned.
所以她是溺死的
Now，since I'm not a complete idiot，
我不是白痴
would you like to tell me what we're really looking for？
请告诉我，你到底在找什么？
Mr。Clemens.
克莱门斯先生
Superintendent.
狱长
I don't believe you've met Lieutenant Ripley.
你还没见过蕾普莉中尉
What's going on，Mr。Clemens？
这是怎么回事，克莱门斯先生？
That's right，sir。What's going on，Mr。Clemens？
是的，长官，怎么了？
Well，first-
首先
the lieutenant is feeling much better，I'm happy to say.
我很高兴蕾普莉中尉，已经觉得好很多
Second，in the interest of public health，
另外，基于公共卫生
- I am performing an autopsy。- Without my authority.
- 我正在验尸 - 没有我的同意？
Well，there didn't seem to be time.
我来不及向你请示
But it's turned out all right.
结果一切无碍
- There's no sign of contagion in the body。- Good.
- 没有感染 - 很好
But it might be helpful if Lt。Ripley didn't parade around in front of the prisoners，
蕾普莉中尉最好别在囚犯面前走动
as I am told she did in the last hour.
听说她已经这么做过
It might also be helpful…
这对我很有帮助…
if you kept me informed as to any change in her physical status.
她的状况若有变化，你也要让我知道
Or would that be asking too much？
这要求过分吗？
We have to cremate the bodies.
尸体必须火葬
Nonsense。We'll keep the bodies on ice till the rescue team arrives.
胡扯，我们要保存尸体，直到救援小组到达
- On ice。- There is the public health issue.
- 冷藏保存 - 这会影响公共卫生
The lieutenant feels that there is still a possibility of a communicable infection.
蕾中尉认为目前仍有传染病存在的可能
I thought you said there was no sign of disease.
你不是说没有疾病征状？
It would appear that the child drowned.
这孩子看来是溺死的
But without the benefit of proper laboratory tests，
不过未经化验
it's impossible to be absolutely certain.
是不可能完全确定的
I would consider it unwise…
我认为不该忽视…
to tolerate even the possibility of an unwelcome virus.
感染病毒的可能
An outbreak of cholera would look extremely bad on a report.
要是霍乱突然蔓延，你一定会面目无光
Would it not，sir？
是不是，长官？
We've 25 prisoners in this facility.
这所监狱的25名囚犯
All double-y-chromos.
全都有双Y染色体
All thieves，rapists，murderers，child molesters。All scum.
全是小偷、强奸犯、杀人犯，全都是人渣
Just because they've taken on religion doesn't make them any less dangerous.
他们信教，并不代表他们很安全
I try not to offend their convictions.
我不干涉他们的信仰
I don't want to upset the order.
也不想扰乱这里的秩序
I don't want ripples in the water.
我不想引发风波
And I don't want a woman walking around giving them ideas.
我也不让女人勾起他们的邪念
I see。For my own personal safety.
我懂了，为我自身安全着想
Exactly.
一点也没错
I will leave the details of the cremation to you，Mr。Clemens.
我把火葬的事交给你，克莱门斯先生
They may use the furnace，but I want everyone back in lockup by 2200 hours.
他们可以用熔炉，不过十点以前要回牢房
You called it，sir.
我保证
- Ah，Christmas has come early，Murph。- What do you mean？
- 圣诞节提早到来 - 什么意思？
- Any dead ox is a good ox。- You're bloody right.
- 有死牛就是好的 - 没错
Smelly bastards，all covered in lice.
满身跳蚤的臭东西
There's only seven of the friggin' things left，and then we're done with them.
现在只剩下七只，就算处理完了
God，I hates hosin' these bastards down.
最讨厌冲洗这臭东西
I always get shite all over me boots.
每次搞得我浑身是粪
Talkin' of hosing things down，Frank-Yeah？
说起臭东西，对了，弗兰克
You had the chance，what would you say to her？
有机会的话，你想跟她说什么？
- What do you mean，if I got the chance？- You know.
- 什么意思？- 你知道的
If you got the chance。You mean，casual like？
有机会的话，你是说平常的时候吗？
Yeah。I mean，how would you put it to her if you bumped into her in the mess hall or somewhere？
对，要是在饭堂遇到，你会说什么？
No problem！
没问题！
I've never had any problem with the ladies.
我对女人很有办法
I'd say to her，「Good day，my dear。How's it goin'？
我会说：「午安，亲爱的，好吗？
Anything I can do to be of service？「
我可以帮你做什么吗？「
Then I'd give her the look，you know-up and down.
然后看着她，从上看到下
And I'd give her the wink，the dirty smile.
然后眨眼睛，色迷迷的笑
- She'd soon get the picture。- Yeah，right.
- 她就会明白 - 没错
And then she'd say，「Kiss my ass，you horny old fucker！」
她就会说：「来亲我吧，老色鬼」
I'd be happy to kiss her ass.
我会去亲她
I'd be happy to kiss her anywhere she wants.
我会去亲她，浑身上下
- Yeah，but treat 'em mean，keep 'em keen。Right，Frank？- Told you before，Murph.
- 对，但要粗暴点，激烈点，明白吗？- 告诉你，墨菲
Treat a queen like a whore and a whore like a queen.
把王后当妓女，把妓女当是王后
Can't go wrong.
不会错的
What do you think killed Babe？
那女孩是怎么死的？
Beats me。She just keeled over.
不知道，反正已归西
- How old was she？- The charts say 11 .
- 她多大？- 11岁吧
In her prime。Never mind.
正值青春，算了
- We'll chop her up later and throw her in the stew。- Right.
- 等一下切碎了，一样要丢进炉里 - 对
Hey，Frank.
弗兰克
What's this？
那是什么？
「We commit this child…
「这孩子…
and this man to your keeping，O Lord.
和这男人，已离开我们的世界
Their bodies…
他们的肉身…
have been taken from the shadow of our nights.
已远离黑暗
They have been released…
他们获得解脱…
from all darkness and pain.「
远离黑暗与痛苦「
「The child and the man…
「这孩子和这男人…
have gone beyond our world.
已离开我们的世界
They are forever eternal…
他们已达到永恒…
and everlasting.
永垂不朽
Ashes to ashes，dust to dust.「
尘归尘，土归土「
Why？
为什么？
Why are the innocent punished？
为什么无辜者受到惩罚？
Why the sacrifice？
为什么必须牺牲？
Why the pain？
为什么有痛苦？
There aren't any promises.
世间原无承诺
Nothing's certain.
世事无常
Only that some get called，some get saved.
少数人能蒙主宠召，得到拯救
She won't ever know the hardship and grief…
她不会了解我们留在人世…
for those of us left behind.
必须面对的困苦和伤痛
We commit these bodies to the void…
我们将遗体交托于虚无…
with a glad heart.
并且满心欢喜
For within each seed，
因为每一颗种子
there is a promise of a flower.
必将长出花朵
And within each death，
每次死亡
no matter how small，
无论多么微不足道
there's always a new life.
总有一个新生命
A new beginning.
一个新的开始
Amen.
阿门
I'll tell you，it's fucking weird.
真奇怪
The only one to survive that crash is a woman.
唯一生还者是女人
What trouble can she cause？
她会制造什么麻烦？
She's already changed everything.
她已经改变这里了
What the fuck are we supposed to do-
我们他妈的该怎么
I，for one-
第一点
I mean it！
我不是开玩笑！
Okay.
好了
There's a lot of talk going around that we've got some disharmony here？
很多谣言说这里不很和谐
Any you guys want to tell me what the problem is？
可以告诉我是什么问题吗？
Come on。Speak to me，brothers.
告诉我，兄弟
All right。I'll tell ya.
我告诉你
I don't mind the dark。I don't mind the bugs.
我不怕黑暗和虫子
I don't mind wanderin' around in some cold，wet，damp tunnel for a week at a time.
也不怕每周一次走进又湿又冷的隧道中
I don't mind anything。But I mind Golic.
我什么也不怕，但我讨厌葛立
That the way you feel about it？
是这样吗？
Yeah。The guy's crazy and he smells bad.
对，他又臭又疯疯癫癫
I ain't going out with him anymore.
我不要再和他一起出去
You got anything to say for yourself？
你有什么话要说？
Well，he's going with you.
他还是得跟着你们
Golic is just another poor，miserable，suffering son of a bitch，just like you and me.
葛立只是个可怜的废人，和你我没有不同
- 'Cept he smells worse。- And he's crazy.
- 他很臭 - 还疯疯癫癫
Knock off the shit！
少跟我来这套！
You got a job to do.
你们有事要做
I don't want to hear another word about Golic.
我不要再听到任何有关葛立的事
Okay？
知道吗？
Well，hello.
你好
As I thought，Mr。Aaron.
亚伦先生，如我所想
- As I thought。- You called it，sir.
- 如我所想 - 你作主吧，长官
I just wanted to，uh，say thanks for what you said at the funeral。It was，uh-
我只想谢谢你在葬体说的话
My friends would have appreciated it.
我的朋友一定会很感激
Yeah，well，you don't wanna know me，lady.
你不会想认识我，小姐
I'm a murderer and rapist of women.
我是专杀女人的强奸犯
Really？
真的？
Well，I guess I must make you nervous.
我猜我一定令你很紧张
- Do you have any faith，sister？- Not much.
- 你有任何信仰吗，妹子？- 谈不上
Well，we've got a lot of faith here。Enough even for you.
这里有很足够的信仰，甚至足够让你加入
I thought women weren't allowed.
我以为女人不准加入
Well，we've never had any before，
以前从未有过女人
but we tolerate anybody.
不过我们容忍任何人
- Even the intolerable。- Thank you.
- 甚至令人无法容忍的人 - 谢谢
That's just a statement of principle。Nothing personal.
这只是原则，不是针对你
You see，we've got a good place to wait here.
在这里等待最好
And until now，no temptation.
直到现在…没有任何诱惑
What are you waiting for？
你们在等什么？
We're waiting for God to return…
等上帝回来…
and raise his servants to redemption.
救赎我们
Dillon and the rest of the alternative people…
五年前迪伦和其他人…
embraced religion，as it were，about five years ago.
接受宗教信仰
- Tincture？- I'm on medication.
- 再喝一杯 - 我正在服药
- Hardly。- What kind of religion？
- 不见得吧 - 哪一种宗教？
Some sort of apocalyptic，millenarian，Christian fundamentalist，uh-
某种相信千年末世的，基督教原教旨主义派
- Right。- Exactly.
- 对 - 正是
Point is，when the company wanted to close the facility down，
问题是公司想关闭监狱
Dillon and the rest of the converts wanted to stay.
迪伦和其他人希望留下
And they were allowed to remain as custodians…
他们获准以守卫身份留下…
with two minders…
加上两名管理员…
and a medical officer.
和一名医疗主任
And here we are.
就是我们
How did you get this wonderful assignment？
你怎么得到这么好的差事？
How do you like your new haircut？
你喜欢这新发型吗？
It's okay.
还算好
Now that I've gone out on a limb for you with Andrews，
我为了你得罪安德鲁斯
damaged my already less-than-perfect relationship with that good man，
我和那好人的关系现在更加恶化
and briefed you…
我也向你说过…
on the humdrum history of Fury 161 ，
复仇161星的无聊历史
can you not tell me what you were looking for in the girl？
可否告诉我在女孩体内找什么？
You attracted to me？
觉得我有吸引力吗？
ln what way？
哪一方面？
ln that way.
「那」方面
Very direct.
你很直接
I've been out here a long time.
我流浪了很久
So have I.
我也是
Yech！
恶心！
Hey，Spike。Spike？Spikey！
嘿！史派克！
Are you down there？What are you doing？
你在下面吗？在做什么？
I really appreciate your affections，
蒙你垂青我真的很感激
but I am aware that they… deflected my question.
但我注意到你回避我的问题
In the nicest possible way，of course.
当然你用的方法很巧妙
You're spoiling the mood.
你真扫兴
I have a job to do.
我得尽我的职责
I just want to know why we had to cremate the bodies.
我只想知道为何要火葬
And now that I'm in your cot，
你认为既然上了你的床
you think I owe you an answer.
就应该回答你
I think you owe me an answer.
你得给我一个理由
Being in my bed's got nothing to do with it.
但这与上不上床无关
I had a terrible dream in hypersleep.
我在长眠期间发了可怕的梦
And I had to be sure what killed her.
我得知道是什么害死她
Anyway，I made a mistake.
我可能错了
Possibly.
有可能
And now I've made another mistake.
现在我又犯了错
Really？What's that？
真的？什么错？
Fraternizing with a prisoner.
和囚犯搞关系
Physical contact。It's against the rules，isn't it？
肉体接触，这触犯规律，对吧？
- Definitely。- When was this？
- 当然 - 几时发生的？
l think you know.
你应该很清楚
I'm not a prisoner.
我不是囚犯
You have a bar code on the back of your head.
你脑后有一个电脑条码
That does deserve an explanation.
那的确应该解释
But I don't think now is the moment.
不过现在还未到时候
Sorry。We are rather spoiling things，aren't we？
对不起，我令你觉得扫兴
Mr。Clemens.
克莱门斯先生
- Mr。Aaron。- Superintendent Andrews would like you to report…
- 亚伦先生 - 狱长安德鲁斯，要你…
to vent shaft 22 on the second quadrant-now.
马上到22号通风孔
- We've had an accident。- Something serious？
- 发生了意外 - 严重吗？
You could call it that。One of our prisoners has been… diced.
可以这么说，有一名囚犯…被切碎了
Sorry。I have to go.
抱歉，得走了
Official duties.
有职务在身
- Who was it？- Murphy.
- 是谁那么倒霉？- 墨菲
How do you know？
你怎么知道的？
That's his boot.
那是他的靴子
I gave him the assignment，sir。He was a wanker.
是我派他来的，他是个笨蛋
No apologies，Mr。Aaron。It wasn't your fault.
别自责，亚伦先生，不是你的错
Well，not much to say，is there？
没什么好说的
- Death was instantaneous。- No shit.
- 他当场死亡 - 可不是
I take it he was pulled into the fan.
我猜他被吸入风扇
Sudden rush of air，I'd imagine，except-
突然而来的一阵风
Right。Almost happened to me once.
对，我也差点被卷进风扇
I've told him so many times，「Stay away from the fans.」
我说过多少次，离风扇远点
Nobody bloody listens.
没有人肯听
Except the fan was blowing.
除了风扇一直吹着
- What's that？- I don't know.
- 那是什么？- 不知道
I want to see you in my quarters in 30 minutes，if you'll please，Mr。Clemens.
半小时后来见我，克莱门斯先生
Have you got any ideas？
你有头绪吗？
Here you are。You know，wandering around without an escort…
你在这儿，你一个人到处乱走…
is really gonna piss Superintendent Andrews off.
会气死安德鲁斯
Will you tell me about your accident？
那件意外是怎么回事？
One of the prisoners has been killed.
一名囚犯死了
Really？How？Hmm.
真的？怎么死的？
In the air shaft.
在通风孔
Poor soul backed into a nine-foot fan.
可怜的家伙，掉进9尺长的风扇
I found something at the accident site，
我在离现场不远
just a bit away from where it happened.
发现一样东西
A mark。A burn.
一个印痕，烧过的痕迹
Rather like the one you found on the girl's cryo-tube.
就像你在那女孩的低温舱，所发现的
Look。I'm on your side.
听着，我跟你同一阵线
I want to help，but I need to know what's going on…
我想帮你，但我要知道这是怎么回事…
or what you think is going on.
或是你认为这是怎么回事
lf you really wanna help，
若你想帮我
find me a computer with audio capabilities…
就找一部语音电脑…
so I can access this flight recorder.
让我解读航行记录器
We don't have anything like that here.
这里没有那种设备
- Well，what about Bishop？- Bishop？
- 主教呢？- 主教？
The droid that crashed with me.
跟我一起坠机的生化人？
I can point you in the right direction.
我只能指给你看
I can't join you.
不能陪你去
I have a previous engagement.
我和别人有约
This'll top you up。Golic，don't fidget.
掉下来了，葛立，不要乱弄
What's all this shit？It's not properly wrapped.
怎么会这样？根本没有包好
- What the hell does he ever do right？- Eat.
- 他笨头笨脑 - 只会吃
- He's got that down pretty good。- Golic！
- 脑满肠肥 - 葛立！
- You light a candle for Murphy。- I'll light a thousand.
- 你为墨菲点枝蜡烛 - 我会点很多支
He was special.
他真好
Never complained about me once.
从未抱怨过
I loved him.
我喜欢他
Is it true what they say？
真的是那样吗？
His head split into a million pieces？
他的头被打碎了？
Okay。Who's got the matches？
谁有火柴？
- Sit down，Mr。Clemens。- Thank you.
- 克莱门斯先生，请坐 - 谢谢
- Sugar？- Uh，no thanks.
- 加糖？- 不用
- Milk？- Just a little，please.
- 加奶？- 一点点
Thank you，Mr。Aaron.
谢谢，亚伦先生
Listen to me，you piece of shit.
给我听好，你这浑蛋
You screw with me one more time，I'll cut you in half.
你再耍我，我就斩开你两半
I'm sorry。I don't think I understand.
对不起，我听不懂
At 0700 hours，I received word from the network.
七点我接到总公司的消息
I may point out this is the first high-level communication…
据我所知，那是这儿…
this installation has ever received，to my knowledge.
收到的第一份高阶层讯息
They want this woman looked after.
他们要我们看牢这女人
- They consider her to be very high priority。- Why？
- 她是最高优先考虑 - 为什么？
l have no idea.
我也不知道
But why did you let her out of the infirmary？
你为何让她离开医疗室？
This accident with Murphy is what happens…
墨菲发生意外是因为…
when one of these dumb sons of a bitches walks around with a hard-on.
你让人满脑子歪念乱跑
I'm a doctor。You're the jailer.
我是医生，你是狱卒
We both know exactly what you are.
我们都知道你的真面目
Sit down。I think it might be better if I left.
坐下，我认为我最好离开
I find you… unpleasant to be around.
在你身边令我非常不愉快
You do？Isn't that lovely？Consider this，Mr。Clemens.
是吗？你要想想，克莱门斯先生
How would you like me to explain your sordid history…
你要我把你的臭史…
to your newfound friend？
告诉你的新朋友吗？
For her personal edification，of course.
为了她个人的想法
Now sit the hell down.
给我坐下来
I don't like you。You're unpredictable.
我不喜欢你，你喜怒无常
Insolent。Possibly dangerous.
傲慢无理，也可能很危险
You question everything！
你对任何事都有疑问！
If I didn't need a medical officer，
如果这里不需要医疗主任
I wouldn't let you within light years of this operation.
我马上要你滚蛋
- I'm eternally grateful。- Keep your sarcasms to yourself.
- 我感激不尽 - 少讲风凉话
Now，is there anything I should know？
现在…我该知道什么事？
- About what？- About the woman.
- 关于什么？- 那女人
Don't play with me，Mr。Clemens。You spend every second you can with her.
少骗我，你几乎随时在她旁边
And I have my suspicions not all of your concerns with her are medical.
鬼才相信你是为了治疗
Has she said anything to you-anything about where she's from，what her mission is？
她跟你说过什么？她从哪里来？有什么任务？
What the hell she was doing in an E.E.V.？
为什么会在逃生艇内？
She told me she was part of a combat unit that came to grief.
她说她们打了败仗
Beyond that，I assume it's all classified.
我想其他都是机密
I haven't pressed her for more.
我没再给她压力
- That's all？- That's all.
- 就这样？- 就这样
- You're sure？- Yes.
- 真的吗？- 对
- Nothing more？- No.
- 没有了？- 没有
Get out of here.
滚出去！
Shut up，you fuckin' bitch！
闭嘴！婊子！
- Get in there！- Shut up，you bitch！
- 进去！- 闭嘴！贱人！
- Nobody's gonna hear you。- Goddamn it，let go of me！
- 没人听得见你 - 他妈的！放开我！
Fuck you！No！
去你的！不！
Hold still！Shh！Shh！
不要动
No！Goddamn it！
不！见鬼！
You okay？
你没事吧？
No！Son of a bitch！
你这王八蛋
Take off。I gotta reeducate some of the brothers.
快走，我得重新教育几位弟兄
We've gotta discuss some matters of the spirit.
谈一下心灵改革的问题
Cigarettes！
香烟！
So let's do it.
干吧
This is like 10 city blocks.
这里有十条街这么长
- How many？- This makes 176.
- 有多少？- 这是第176个
Can't you chew a little quieter？
吃东西小声点
I'm trying to figure out how big this compartment is.
我正在算这区段有多大
I can't think with all this goddamn noise you're making.
你这么吵我无法思考
- You're not supposed to swear。- I'm sorry.
- 别说脏话 - 对不起
- Now，we've encircled this entire compartment once。- Hey.
- 我们绕行过整个区段 - 嘿！
What？
干嘛？
What the shit is doing that？
什么狗屁玩意？
- Swearing。- Shut up.
- 说脏话 - 闭嘴
It's all right to say 「shit.」 It ain't against God.
说「狗屁」没关系，我又没骂上帝
What the hell is going on with the candles？
蜡烛怎么了？
Must be the wind from one of the vent shafts.
一定是附近通风孔
Backwash from the closest circulating unit.
吹来的逆风
But if all the candles go out，how the hell we gonna know where we are？
要是蜡烛都被吹熄，我们怎么知道位置？
Somebody will just have to go back and relight them.
只好派人回去重新点亮
I guess I'm nominated.
我去吧
Watch your step，brother.
小心点，兄弟
Okay，who are the comedians？
好了，谁在开玩笑？
Wait，wait，wait！
等等！等等！
- Quick，grab it。Here。- Help me！Help me！
- 快跑！快！抓住！- 救我！救我！
Go！Fuckin' go！
走！快走！
Go，go，go！Quick！Run！
走！走！快点！
Gimme that！
拿来！
Get this fucking thing off me！
把这臭东西弄掉！
Oh，fuck！
操！
Let me go！
放开我！
Hey.
嘿！
Ah，Ripley.
蕾普莉！
Hi，Bishop。How you feeling？
嗨！主教，你感觉如何？
My legs hurt.
我的腿很痛
Uh，listen，I'm sorry.
我很难过
It's okay。I'm just a glorified toaster.
没关系，我只是个烤面包机
How are you？
你还好吗？
I like your new haircut.
我喜欢你的新发型
Bishop，can you access data on the flight recorder？
主教，你能查出航行记录器资料？
No problem.
没问题
Golic？
葛立？
- I'm home。- What happened on the Sulaco？
- 好了 - 苏拉可号发生什么事？
Why were our cryo-tubes ejected？
低温舱为何弹射出来？
Stasis interrupted.
静态平衡受干扰
Fire in cryogenic compartment.
低温舱起火
- Repeat。Fire in cryogenic - What happened？
- 重覆，低温舱… - 怎么回事？
What started the fire，Bishop？
怎么起火的，主教？
Can you hear me？
你听得到吗？
The fire was electrical.
电线短路
lt was in the subflooring.
地板的材料烧起来
Did the sensors pick up anything moving around on the ship prior to separation？
救生船脱离母舰前有没有东西在舰上？
It's very dark here，Ripley。I'm not what I used to be.
这儿好暗，蕾普莉，我的视力大不如前
Just tell me。Does the recorder indicate anything？
告诉我，记录器有没有显示？
Was there an alien on board？
舰上有没有异形？
Yes.
有
Is it on the Sulaco or did it come with us on the E.E.V.？
它还在苏拉可号，还是和我们一起坠机？
It was with us all the way.
它一直都和我们一起
Does the company know？
公司知不知道？
The company knows everything that happened on the ship.
公司知道舰上的每一件事
It all goes into the computer and gets sent back to network.
一切都输入电脑，传回总公司
And they want it.
他们还是要异形
I hurt。Do me a favor。Disconnect me.
帮个忙，切断电源
I could be reworked，but I'll never be top of the line again.
就算我被修好，也无法回复正常
I'd rather be nothing.
我宁愿消失
You're sure？
你肯定？
Do it for me，Ripley.
就当为我好吧，蕾普莉
It wasn't me！I didn't do it！
不是我！不是我干的！
It was-It was the dragon.
是…是那一条龙
Feeds on minds。It was-
吸食人的心灵
- Nobody can stop it。- What about Boggs and Rains？
- 谁也无法阻挡 - 博格斯和雷恩斯呢？
- They got s-slaughtered like pigs。- It wasn't me！
- 全像猪一样被宰了 - 不是我！
- It wasn't me！- Stark raving mad.
- 不是我 - 他完全疯了
I'm not saying it was anyone's fault，but he should have been chained up.
早该用铁炼锁住
You called it，sir。Mad as a fucking hatter.
你说得对，长官，他发疯了
Keep him separated from the rest。I don't want him causing a panic.
把他隔离，别引起恐慌
Clemens，sedate this poor idiot。Yeah？
克莱门斯，让这白痴安静下来
Not until we know about the brothers.
我们得先弄清楚弟兄的下落
Now，now。Pull yourself together。Talk to me now.
振作一点，告诉我
- Now，where are Boggs and Rains？- It wasn't me！
- 博格斯和雷恩斯在哪里？- 不是我！
Hopeless。You're not gonna get anything out of him.
没有用，问不出来的
- It wasn't me。- We'll have to send out a search team.
- 不是我！- 我们得派出搜索队
I'm afraid we'll have to assume there's a very good chance…
我恐怕有很大几率…
this simple bastard has murdered them.
这畜牲会杀了他们
Now，you don't know that.
你还不知道
He's never lied to me.
他没骗过我
He's crazy，he's a fool，but he's not a liar.
他是个疯疯癫癫的傻子，不过他不会说谎
He's telling the truth.
他说的是实话
I'd like to talk to him about this-this dragon.
我想跟他谈谈这条龙
- It was a dragon。- You're not talking to anyone，Lieutenant.
- 那是一条龙 - 你别想跟任何人说话，中尉
I'm not interested in your opinion，
我对你的意见没兴趣
because you are not in full possession of the facts.
你根本搞不清状况
This man is a convicted multiple murderer，known for particularly brutal crimes.
他曾犯下多宗杀人案，是个残忍的凶手
Isn't that right，Mr。Dillon？
对不对，迪伦先生？
Yeah。That part's right.
对…那是真的
Then I'll talk to you。It's important.
那我就和你谈，这很重要
When I have finished with my official duties，
我完成职务后
I will be quite pleased to have a little chat，yes？
很乐意和你谈
Let me see if I have this correct，Lieutenant。It's an eight-foot creature of some kind，
让我弄清楚，中尉，这生物有8尺高
with acid for blood，and it arrived on your spaceship.
血液是强酸，坐你的太空船到达此地
It kills on sight and is generally unpleasant.
它见人就杀，性情不太友善
And，of course，you expect me to accept all this on your word.
你当然期望我信你的话
No，I don't expect anything.
不，我不期望任何事
- Quite a story，Mr。Aaron。- Right，sir。It's a beauty.
- 故事很精彩，亚伦先生 - 是的，很精彩
- Never heard anything quite like it，sir。- Expect not.
- 我没听过这种故事 - 我想也没有
Tell me，Lieutenant，what would you suggest we do？
告诉我，你建议我们怎么做？
Well，what kind of weapons have you got？
你们有什么武器？
This is a prison.
这是监狱
It's not a good idea to allow prisoners access to firearms.
不能让囚犯碰武器
What keeps them from killing you？
以免他们杀了你？
Fear。There's no way to escape.
是的，它根本逃不出去
With the arrival of the next supply ship，the company would eliminate them.
下一班补给船到达时，公司会派人消灭它
This is a maximum security prison，
这是个最高设防的监狱
and you have no weapons of any kind？
你们却没有任何武器？
We have some carving knives in the abattoir。A few more in the mess hall.
屠宰场有几把屠刀，饭堂也有
Some fire axes scattered about the place。Nothing terribly formidable.
还有几把消防斧头，没有太多厉害武器
That's all？
只有这些？
We're on the honor system.
我们推行荣誉制度
- Then we're fucked。- No，you're fucked.
- 我们完蛋了 - 不，只有你完蛋了
Confined to the infirmary。Quarantined.
我把你关在医疗室
Mr。Aaron will escort you.
亚伦先生会护送你去
I think you'll be safe from any large，nasty beast while you're there，right？
你在那儿最安全，对吗？
Yes，that's a good girl.
这才乖
Let's all report to the mess hall.
全体到饭堂报到
Superintendent Andrews wants a meeting。Mess hall，right away，people.
狱长安德鲁斯要开会，立刻到饭堂报到
Isn't there any way off of this place？Some way to escape？
能不能离开？有办法逃生？
No。Supply ship comes every six months.
补给船每六个月来一次
- And that's it？- Mm-hmm.
- 只有这样？- 是的
Fuck.
可恶
They are sending somebody to pick you up quite soon，I gather.
很快就有人来接你
Really.What's 「soon」？
很快是多快？
I don't know。Nobody's ever been in a hurry to get here before.
不知道，以前没有人急着来这里
Do you want to tell me what you and Andrews talked about？
跟我说，安德鲁斯和你谈些什么？
No.
不
You'll just say I'm crazy.
你会说我疯了
That's a bit uncharitable.
这么说有点不厚道
How are you feeling？
你感觉如何？
Not so hot.
不太好
Sore throat.
喉咙痛
Sick to my stomach。Pissed off.
胃部不舒服，而且气坏了
Well，that's understandable given the circumstances.
在这种情况下我能了解
Perhaps I should give you one of my special cocktails.
也许我该给你打一剂特别的药
I don't know why everybody blames everybody for everything.
为什么大家都互相指责？
Nobody's persect，only human.
人非圣贤，我们只是凡人
There's no such thing as a perfect human.
没有一个人是完美的
In an insane world，
这里是疯狂世界
a sane man…
正常人…
must… appear… insane.
也要变成疯子
- That's very profound，Golic。- Thank you.
- 讲得真好，葛立 - 谢谢
You married？
你结婚了吗？
- Me？- You should get married，have kids.
- 我？- 你应该结婚生子
Pretty girl。I used to know lots of 'em back home.
你这么漂亮，我曾认识很多漂亮女孩
They used to like me.
她们很喜欢我
For a while.
过一阵子就变心
You're gonna die too.
你也会死的
- Are you？- What？
- 你有没有？- 什么？
Married.
结婚
Why？
干嘛？
- Just curious。- No.
- 只是好奇 - 没有
- How about leveling with me？- Could you be more specific？
- 你也坦白点，如何？- 讲清楚一点
When I asked how you got assigned here，you avoided the question.
你没说你为何被派来这里
And then when I asked about the prison I.D。tattooed on the back of your head，
我提到你脑后的监狱识别条码
you ducked me again.
你又顾左右而言他
It's a long，sad story…
说来话长，令人伤心…
and more than a little melodramatic.
而且通俗煽情
Try me.
说来听听
If you insist.
既然你这么想听
After my student years，
我毕业以后
despite the fact that I had become…
虽然我已经…
secretly addicted to morphine，
对吗啡上瘾
I was considered to be most promising，
我仍被认为是
a man with a future.
最有前途的医生
And during my first residency，I did a 36-hour stretch on an E.R.
我当专科实习医生在急诊室当值36小时
So，I went out and I got more than a little drunk.
我跑出去喝得酩酊大醉
Then I got called back.
然后我又被召回
Boiler had blown on a fuel plant，
一座炼油厂的蒸汽炉爆炸
and there were 30 casualties.
30名伤者
And 11 of them died.
11人死亡
Not as a result of the accident…
不是因为意外…
but because I prescribed the wrong dosage of painkiller.
而是因为我开错止痛药剂量
I got seven years in prison and my license reduced to a 3-C.
我服刑七年，执照被降为3C
At least I got off the morphine.
至少我戒掉吗啡瘾
l'm sorry.
很遗憾
l think I was let off lightly.
我的惩罚还算轻
Did you serve your time here？
你在这里服刑？
I got to know this motley crew quite well.
我和这群乌合之众混熟了
So when they stayed，I stayed.
他们留下来，我也留下了
Nobody else would employ me.
没有人愿意聘用我
So，do you still trust me with a needle？
你还愿意让我打针吗？
Magnificent.
很好
Give us strength，O Lord，to endure.
主呀，给我们力量来坚守
We recognize that we are poor sinners in the hands of an angry God.
我们只是上帝手中卑微的罪人
Let the circle be unbroken until the day。Amen.
请以手包围我们，守护我们
- Amen。- What the fuck is happening here？
- 阿门 - 这里出了什么事？
What the fuck is this bullshit that's comin' down？
出了这么一大堆事情
We got murder。We got rape。We got brothers in trouble.
有人死了，有人要强暴，弟兄出了麻烦
I don't want no more bullshit around here！
不要再闹事了！
Now，we got problems，we stand together.
出了问题，我们要团结
Yes。Thank you，Mr。Dillon。All right.
是的，谢谢，迪伦先生
Once again，this is rumor control.
再一次，这是谣言管制会议
Here are the facts.
以下是案情
At 0800 hours，prisoner Murphy，
早上八点，囚犯墨菲
through carelessness on his part，
因为粗心
was found dead in vent shaft 17.
在第17通风孔死去
He seems to have been sucked into a ventilator fan.
他似乎被吸入通风扇门
At about 21 hours，
晚上九点
prisoner Golic reappeared in a deranged state.
囚犯葛立出现精神错乱
Prisoners Boggs and Rains are missing.
囚犯博格斯和雷恩斯失踪
There seems to be a good chance that they have met with foul play…
很可能是遇害…
at the hands of prisoner Golic.
遭囚犯葛立杀害
We need to organize and send out a search party.
我们必须组组一支搜索队
Volunteers will be appreciated.
有人自愿我们会很感激
I think it's fair to say that our smoothly running facility…
这座监狱一直相安无事…
has suddenly developed a few problems.
突然出现一些问题
I can only hope we are able to all pull together over the next few days…
希望大家能在这几天提起精神…
until the rescue team arrives for Lieutenant Ripley.
直到救援小组接走蕾普莉中尉
It's here！It got Clemens！
它来了，它杀死克莱门斯！
- Stop this raving at once！Stop it！- I'm telling you，it's here！
- 马上停止这种谣言 - 我跟你说它来了！
Aaron，get that foolish woman back to the infirmary！
亚伦，把那笨女人带回医疗室！
Move it！
快跑！
Out of my way！
让开！
Fuck！
可恶！
We give you thanks，O Lord.
主呀，我们感谢你
Your wrath has come，and the time is near for us to be judged.
您的愤怒已显现，我们知道审判快到
The apocalypse is upon us.
世界末日将要降临
Let us be ready。Let your mercy be just.
让我们有所准备，得到您的饶恕
- It was massive。- Amen！
- 好可怕 - 阿门
- And fast。- I was there。I saw it.
- 速度 - 我在那里，我看到了
What the fuck do we do now？Who's in fucking charge？
现在该怎么办？谁来指挥？
Organize。We gotta organize，right？
我们得组组起来，对吧？
Right。Well，I guess I'm next in line.
对，我有指挥权
- 85's gonna be in charge。Jesus，give us a break！- Don't call me that.
- 让85指挥？完了 - 别那么叫我
Okay，look。There's no way I can replace Andrews.
我不可能取代安德鲁斯
He was a good man。I know you guys didn't appreciate him.
他是好人，虽然你们不喜欢他
Aaron，we don't want to hear that shit now.
亚伦，我们不想听屁话
Hey，sister，what about you？You're an officer.
妹子，你呢？你是个军官
How about showing us a little leadership？
展露一点领导才能吧？
Forget fucking Shirley Temple。You take charge.
别管她 你来指挥
- Right。- You run things here anyway.
- 对 - 反正这里都是你在管
No fuckin' way。I'm not the officer type.
不可能 我没当官的材料
I just take care of my own.
我只会管我自己
Well，what does this fucking beast want？
这臭怪物想要什么？
Is this mother gonna try for us all？
这老妈到底指不指挥？
- Yeah。- Well，ain't that sweet？
- 要 - 这下可好
So how are we gonna stop it？
你想怎么阻止它？
- We have no weapons。Is that correct？- Right.
- 我们没有武器，对吧？- 对
I haven't seen one exactly like this before.
我看到的和这只不一样
Moves differently.
它的动作有点不同
But the others were afraid of fire-
其他那些什么都不怕
not much else.
只怕火
- Can we seal off this area？- No chance.
- 能不能封锁这地方？- 没办法
The installation's 10 miles square.
这个监狱10平方英里
- There's 600 air ducts running to the surface。- What about video？
- 共有六百个通气管 - 录影设备呢？
I see these closed-circuit monitors everywhere。We could try to find it that way.
这里到处都有闭路电视系统
The video system hasn't worked in years。Nothing much works here.
闭路电视系统多年没用，这里什么都不能用
We got a lot of technology，no way to fix it.
很多科技用品都没办法修好
- What 85 is trying to tell you is… - Don't call me that！
- 85想说的是… - 别那么叫我！
we ain't got no entertainment center，no climate control，
没有娱乐中心，气候控制
no video system，no surveillance，
没有视讯系统，没有监视
no freezers，no fucking ice cream，
没有电雪柜，没有雪糕
no rubbers，no women，no guns.
没有避孕套，没有女人，没有枪
All we got here is shit！
什么都没有！
Oh，what the hell are we even talking to her for？
跟她谈有个屁用？
She's the one that brought the fucker.
她把那臭东西带来
Why don't we just get her head and shove it through the fucking wall？
何不砍下她的头，塞进墙壁？
That sounds good to me.
这样最好
Hey，Morse.
莫尔斯
Why don't you shut the fuck up？
你他妈的闭嘴
Right.
好了
Right。What are we going to do？
我们该怎么办？
What's this？Um，
这是什么？
that leads from the mess hall to the infirmary.
那条通道从饭堂通往医疗室
It's a ventilation shaft.
是个通风孔
Then we go in there，flush it out.
我们从那里进去把它逼出来
Hey。Hey，look，there's miles and miles of tunnel through there.
那里的隧道有好几里长
It won't go far.
它走不了太远
It'll nest in this area.
它会在这里筑巢
Right around…
就在…
- Here。- How do you know that？
- 这附近 - 你怎么知道？
It's like a lion.
它就像只狮子
It sticks close to the zebras.
紧跟着斑马群
Zebras？Oh，right.
斑马？这可好
But，look。Running around down here in the dark-Are you kidding？
这么暗跑来跑去？别开玩笑
Once you get out of this main shaft，there's no overheads.
走出主通风孔就没有电灯
- Don't we have flashlights？- We got thousands of 'em，but no batteries.
- 不是有手电筒吗？- 有几千个，但没有电池
- I told you，nothing works。- Torches？
- 我说了，都废弃了 - 火把呢？
Do we have the capacity to make fire？
我们能生火吧？
Most humans have enjoyed that privilege since the Stone Age.
人类从石器时代起就有这能力
No need to be sarcastic.
你用不着讽刺我
Never been used。They were gonna dump a lot of nuclear crap in there.
这里没用过，这里打算放核废料
Never got around to it。It's clean as a whistle inside.
一直没空，里头空无一物
This the only way in or out？
这里是出入的唯一通道？
That's right。Walls are six feet thick，solid steel.
没错，墙壁有6尺多厚，实心钢造的
Really knew how to build these babies.
建造起来真是大工程
You're saying we get something in there，
任何东西被关进去
there's no way it can get out？
绝对出不来？
That's right。No fucking way.
对，无路可逃
This is where we keep it。I forget what the stuff's called.
我们放在这里，忘了叫什么
- Quinitricetyline。- I knew that.
- 圭乃特利西特林 - 我知道
Right。I've got to get these section arrangements organized with Dillon…
我把工作分配好，让迪伦…
for the paintbrush，uh-
漆油
- So，um - David.
- 现在… - 大卫
- Yeah。You can get these drums organized。- Right，85.
- 你把这些油桶整理好 - 知道了，85
And，uh，don't call me that.
还有…别那么叫我
What's this 「85」 thing？
85到底是什么意思？
Couple of us sneaked a look at his personnel file the day he arrived.
我们偷看过他的档案
It's his I.Q.
那是他的智商
I saw a drum of this stuff…
我看过这种油桶…
fall into a beachhead bunker once.
掉在海滩木屋
The blast put a tug in dry dock for 17 weeks.
爆炸令码头三个半月没有鱼群
Great stuff！
厉害的玩意！
All right。Let me get this straight.
让我搞清楚
You want to burn it down and out of the pipes，
你想用火把它烧出通风管
force it in here，slam the door…
逼进这里，把门锁上…
- and trap its ass？- Right.
- 然后把它困住？- 对
And you want help from us y-chromo boys，huh？
你要我们这些天生罪犯帮忙？
You got something better to do？
你有别的事要做吗？
Why should we put our ass on the line for you？
我们为何要替你冒险拼命？
Your ass is already on the line.
你们早就有危险
The only question is…
问题是…
what are you gonna do about it？
你打算怎么办？
Look at this.
你看
There's only one of these fucking batteries in 2，000 that works.
两千个电池，只有一个用得着
Hey，it could have been a lot worse。Yeah？
还未算最糟
We might have got the paintbrush detail.
可能照不亮
Man，this stuff stinks.
这玩意真臭
- This shit smells awful。- Then don't breathe the fucking fumes.
- 真的要臭死人了 - 那就别呼吸
- I'm in a fucking pipe with it。- How can I keep from breathing it！
- 应该要戴氧气筒 - 你要我闷死！
I mean，don't breathe too hard.
不要深呼吸
- You'll get high。- That's good for me.
- 你会很兴奋 - 感情好
So you miss Doc，right？
你想念医生，对吧？
What makes you say that？
你怎么这么说？
I thought you two got real close.
你们两个很亲密
I guess you've been looking through some keyholes.
我猜你很爱偷窥
That's what I thought。Oh！
我是那么想的！
- You okay？- Yeah。l'm fine.
- 你还好吗？- 还好
Whatever you say，but，uh，you don't look okay to me，sister.
真的吗？可是你看起来不太好
l'm fine.
我很好
I hate this place。I hate this place.
我讨厌这地方
Well.
嗯
There's definitely something in here with us.
除了我们，绝对还有别的东西
Okay。Don't light the fire until I give the signal.
我没打信号别点火
This is the signal.
这是信号
Got it？Can you remember that？
懂吗？记得住吗？
Shit！
糟糕！
Buh-
巴哈
Wait for the fucking signal！
怎么不等信号？
Get down！
趴下！
Come on，come on！We gotta find the sprinklers！
快点，我们得找出洒水器
Come on！We gotta help these guys！
快救他们！
Come on！Move！Move！
快点！跑呀！
Go to the waste dump。Don't open the doors！
到废料处理场，别开门！
- Oh，God！- It's all right.
- 天啊！- 不会有事的
It's all right。You're gonna be all right。We got you.
你会没事的，我们一定会救你
Fire's out.
火熄了
Junior！Junior！Get those sprinklers and turn them on.
朱德，去把洒水器打开
We gotta get him out of here.
快带他出去
Come on。We're walking you out.
我们带你出去
Junior！Behind you！
它在你后面！
Open the door！
开门！
Come on！Come on！
快点！快点！
Come and get me，fucker！
来捉我呀！混蛋！
Even for those who have fallen，
虽然他们受难
this is a time of rejoicing.
我们仍应欣慰
We salute their courage.
向他们的勇气致敬
They will live forever.
他们会永垂不朽
Those that are dead are not dead.
死亡并不代表真正死去
They have moved up.
他们升上天去
They have moved to a higher place.
到了更高的境界
Crazy bastards.
疯子
Andrews used to call them Dillon's God Squad。Keeps 'em out of mischief.
克莱门斯常叫做迪伦圣兵 令他们幸免于难
- You're not the religious type。- Me？
- 你不信宗教？- 我？
Shit，no。I've got a job.
才不，我要工作
Look，uh-
听着
Figure the rescue team gets here in four，five days-
我想救援队四五天就会到了
six，tops.
顶多是六天
They open the door，go in there with smart guns and kill it.
他们一来，拿出机关枪轰死它
- What have you heard from them？- Nothing much.
- 有消息吗？- 没有
We got a message received.
只说收到讯息
Later，we got something that said you were top priority.
后来又说，你是最高优先考虑
They don't cut us in on much.
什么也不说
We're the ass end of the totem pole out here.
因为我们在边疆
What if they don't want to kill it？
要是他们不想杀怪物呢？
- Take it back？- Yeah.
- 带回去吗？- 是的
They're not lunatics，you know？Gotta kill it.
他们疯了，一定要杀了它
Right？
对吗？
Morse，please，cut me loose.
莫尔斯，把我放开
No fucking way.
不可以
Come on，man。It hurts.
很痛
Oh，sorry.
抱歉
Come on。I haven't done nothing.
我没做什么
- Just don't talk to me。- Please，what did I do？Please.
- 不要和我说话 - 拜托，我做了什么？
I'll tell you what I'm gonna do。I'm gonna sit here and guard your ass like l'm supposed to.
告诉你我要怎么做，我要看管着你，那是我的事
I don't need any fucking trouble with Dillon.
我不想惹怒迪伦
All I did was tell 'em about the dragon，what it did to Boggs and Rains.
我只告诉他，那条龙杀了博格斯和雷恩斯
I didn't lie。You saw it.
我没说谎，你看到了
Fuckin' 「A」 I saw it.
可恶，我看到了
Oh，please.
拜托
If this gets in here，I'm dead。I can't run.
它一进来，我就死了，我跑不了
It's not going to get in here。We got it trapped.
它不会来的，它会被困住
So what's the big deal？Come on。Let me loose，man.
那也不会怎样，快点，放开我
- Don't I always give you cigarettes first？- Yeah.
- 我每次都先给你烟 - 是的
Aren't I your friend？
我不是你朋友吗？
I love you，Morse.
我爱你，莫尔斯
Why not？
有何不可？
But behave yourself。No fucking around…
乖一点，不准惹事…
or I'll get nothing but shit.
别害我
- So where they got it？- In the waste tank.
- 怪物在哪里？- 在废置炉
We got that sucker nailed。I mean，tight.
把它困住
Gotta see it again.
我想再看看怪物
What the fuck you talking about？
你说什么鬼话？
No more cigarettes for you.
不给你香烟了
Right。We got the first part。Now what do we say？
第一步完成了，要说什么？
Tell them we trapped it.
告诉他们是我们捉的
- What do we call it？- A xenomorph.
- 那叫什么？- 异形怪物
Right.
对
How do you spell it？
怎么拼音？
（捉到异形怪物）
（请批准消灭）
Hey，wait a minute。We can't kill it.
杀不了的
- We don't have any weapons，right？- Right.
- 又没有武器 - 对
（致费欧娜161C级监狱 通讯卫星通报：收到报告）
See？That's all they ever tell us。Treat us like shit.
看吧，就是这样，当我们狗屁
（救援队将在12时抵达）
（不允许消灭异形怪物）
（救援队到达前避免接触）
（要求不批准）
- Off and on me now？- What the hell you talking about？
- 时好时坏 - 你在说什么？
Talk to me，the beast.
说话呀
You can't go in there，dickhead。The big mothersucker will eat you alive.
不可以进去，那怪物会吃掉你的
Sorry.
抱歉！
Sorry，sorry，sorry，sorry，sorry.
抱歉！抱歉！抱歉！
Tell me what to do next.
告诉我要怎么做
So，you're telling me they're coming to take this thing away？
他们要来带走怪物
Yeah，they're gonna try。They don't wanna kill it.
他们会这么做，根本就不杀死
We gotta figure out a way to do it before they come here.
我们得想办法
Why do we have to kill it？You just said the company's coming for it.
为什么我们要杀它？反正公司会来解决
That's right。They wanna take it back.
对，他们是来带走怪物
- Some sort of weapon。- Yeah，what's wrong with that？
- 用作研究武器 - 有何不可？
They can't control it。They don't understand。It'll kill them all.
他们控制不了，他们不知道它的危险性
Like I said，what's wrong with that？
我说了，有何不可？
Nothing's wrong with that… except a lot of innocent people will die.
没有…但很多无辜的人会死
I thought you were a religious man.
我以为你有宗教信仰
You don't understand，do you？
你不明白
That world out there doesn't exist for us anymore.
外面的世界对我们已经不存在
We've got our own little world out here.
我们有自己的世界
It ain't much，but it's ours.
虽然不大，却是我们的
So fuck everybody else.
别人都可以死吗？
No。Fuck them.
不，所有人都可以
- Hey，Dillon？- Yeah？
- 迪伦 - 是
Uh，Dillon，we got a teeny-weeny problem.
迪伦，有个小问题
Fucking great！
这下好了！
Miserable，crazy son of a bitch let him loose.
那疯小子放走怪物
Got what he fucking deserved.
自作自受
Well，now what are we gonna do？
现在怎么办？
Andrews was right。Should've kept the shithead chained up.
安德鲁斯是对的，应该把那小子锁住的
You okay？
你还好吗？
Piss on her。The fucking thing's loose out there。What are we gonna do？
去她的，那怪物还在外面，该怎么办？
l just said that.
我说过了
And you're the dumb prick that let Golic out。You miserable little shit！
你这小王八蛋让葛立逃跑！
Come on。Cut that shit out.
好了，住嘴！
Tell your fucking bozo to shape up！
叫那个小丑识相点！
Wh-Wh-What do you think？
你觉得呢？
I think I have to get to the E.E.V.
到逃生艇
- Why？What's up？- I just have to use the neuroscanner.
- 为什么？- 我们得用神经扫描器
- You don't look so good。- Who gives a shit how she looks？
- 你看来很憔悴 - 管她好不好
- What are we gonna do？- Want a smack in the mouth，you stupid wanker？
- 现在怎么办？- 你想挨揍吗，笨蛋？
Shut the fuck up and stop causing panic！
闭上你的臭嘴，别让大家惊慌！
Panic-You're so fucking stupid，you couldn't spell it。Don't talk to me about panic.
惊慌？你笨得连惊慌也不会写，别和我谈惊慌
- We ought to panic！We're fucking screwed！- Whose fault is that？
- 我们才要恐慌，我们完蛋了！- 到底是谁的错？
All right。Now shut up，both of you！
你们两个闭嘴！
Shut up！
闭嘴！
- Well，I'm out of ideas！- Oh，surprise me.
- 我们都没有办法了 - 不出奇
- What about outside？- Great idea.
- 外面怎么样？- 好主意
Sun don't come up for another two days。It's 40 below zero.
两天后日出，现在零下40度
The rescue team's 10 hours away。So that makes a lot of sense！
救援队10小时后来临，真是秒啊
Wonderful。You just want us to stay here and let this thing have us for lunch！
让那怪物把我们当午餐！
I want you to get everybody that's still left together.
叫所有仍生还的人集合
Get 'em into the assembly hall.
到大厅聚集
Okay.
好的
Where'd she go？
她上哪里去了？
Need any help？
需要帮忙吗？
I don't mean to scare you.
我不是故意吓你
You shouldn't be wandering around alone.
你不应该一个人乱走
Do me a favor and run this keyboard，will you？
帮我个忙，替我按键盘
Okay.
好的
- What do I do？- Hit 「B」 or 「C.」
- 我该怎么做？- 按B或C
What's 「C」？
C是什么？
- 「Display biofunctions.」 - That's it.
- 显示生命机能 - 就是那个
Okay，we're hot。Now what？
行了，现在呢？
Let it run a cycle.
让它转一圈
It's real fuzzy.
很模糊
Hit 「enhancement.」
按放大键
Keep looking.
继续看
I don't know how to read this stuff.
我看不懂这玩意儿
Hemorrhaging will show as a dark patch.
如果出血就有暗色块
Look for…
在头骨根部…
hairline fractures through the base of the skull.
找细微裂痕
Little white lines.
小小的白线
（异体组组）
What is it？
怎么了？
I think you've got one inside of you.
你体内也有一只
That's not possible.
不可能
What does it look like？
什么样子？
（DNA资料扫描中 组组类型不明）
- Horrible。- I have to see it.
- 太可怕了 - 我得看看它
- Freeze it。- You don't want to look at it.
- 定格 - 你最好别看
Freeze it！
定格！
l'm sorry.
我很难过！
All right。The fucking thing is loose。It's out there.
那怪物还在，它逃出来了
A rescue team is on its way with guns and shit.
救援队带着武器，快到达了
Right now there isn't any place that's real safe.
现在危机四伏
But we stay here，in the assembly hall.
大家在这里集合
This place never had any fucking air conditioning.
这里没有空调
If it comes in，it's gotta be through one of these doors.
如果怪物来了，一定走大门
Now we post a guard to let us know if it's coming.
要有人守门，怪物来了才知道
In the meantime，you lay low，be ready and stay right…
现在先躲好，准备好迎接它…
in case your time comes.
万一你的大限来临
Don't you start bullshitting，Dillon.
迪伦，少鬼话连篇
We're gonna be trapped in here like rats.
我们都会被困死在这里的
You got a weapon？You got a blade？Then you take it out and you fucking use it！
有武器小刀的，拿出来用吧！
Oh，right。So you think we're gonna stab this mothersucker to death？
对，用小刀就能杀死怪物？
No，I don't think shit！Maybe.
杀死个毛
Maybe you'll hurt it before it takes you out，huh？
只能在被杀死前令它受伤？
Isn't that something？Any of you got any better ideas？
那是个主意，谁有更好的主意？
And I'll tell you，until the rescue team gets here，we're fucked！
告诉你们，等救援队到达前我们已经死光！
So you better get prepared.
大家先作准备吧
Well，I ain't staying here.
我才不留在这里
Well，then，suit yourself.
随便你
Fire.
点火
- Furnace。- Yeah。Let's make it to the furnace.
- 是熔炉 - 对，我们把它弄到熔炉里
Holy shit.
老天哪
Well，all right.
这下好了
Fuckin' 「A.」
真他妈的
- Fuckin' 「A.」 - Too fuckin' right it's right.
- 真他妈的 - 说得对
It's up。What do you want to say？
设定好了，你想说什么？
Tell them the whole place has gone toxic.
跟他们说这里充满毒气
Are you kidding？
别开玩笑
Then they won't come here。The rescue team will turn back.
救援小组会折返
- Yeah。I know。- What are you talking about？
- 我知道 - 你在胡说什么？
Our only hope is that they kill this fucker.
我们得靠他们杀死怪物
And maybe they can do something for you。I don't know，freeze you-
他们也许能想办法把你冷藏起来
They can do an operation。They've got the technology.
动手术，他们有技术
If this organism gets off the planet，it'll kill everything.
要是异形逃走，就会杀光所有人
The company doesn't care about that.
公司根本不在乎
They just want it for their bioweapons division，okay？
他们只想拿它来研究生化武器
So we can't let them come here.
我们不能让他们来
Fuck you.
管你的
Look，I'm sorry you've got this thing inside you，but l'm getting rescued.
我很遗憾你体内有那东西，可是他们得救我
I don't give a shit about these stupid prisoners，but l've got a wife，a kid.
我才不管那些囚犯，我有老婆、孩子
- I'll go home on the next rotation！- I know。This is hard.
- 下次轮到我回家 - 我知道
I'm gonna send this message。I need that fucking code.
不过我要传送这讯息，我要密码
I'm sorry，babe。It's classified.
抱歉，这是机密
Listen，you stupid little shit！This has got to be done，okay？
你这笨蛋一定要这么做
- There are no alternatives！- No way！
- 别无选择！- 没门
You're not getting it！No fucking way！
我不会给你密码，不可能
Look，it's nothing personal.
听着，我跟你无冤无仇
Understand？
明白吗？
I think you're okay.
我认为你会没有事
Thanks.
谢了
Have you got any ideas？
你有什么主意吗？
It won't kill me.
它不会杀我
I'm carrying the new queen.
我孕育新王后
It won't kill its future.
它不会杀死自己的未来
You really wanna bet this thing's that smart？
那怪物有这么聪明？
Maybe I'll go find it。See how smart it is.
或许我去找它，看它到底有多聪明
- You're gonna go and look for it？- Yeah.
- 你要去找它？- 对
I have a pretty good idea of where it is.
我知道它在哪里
It's just down there… in the basement.
它就在下面，地下室
This whole place is a basement.
这整个地方都是地下室
It's a metaphor。Wanna come？
我只是打个比喻，你来不来？
Fuck me.
我日
（收到逃生艇扫描资料）
（紧急医疗小组将在2小时内到达）
（最高优先考虑：隔离蕾普莉中尉）
（等待确认）
Where are you when I need you？
要找你时你在哪里呢？
Don't be afraid.
别怕
l'm part of the family.
我是你的家人
You've been in my life so long，
你进入我的生命这么久
I can't remember anything else.
我已经不记得其他事情
Now do something for me.
现在帮我个忙吧
It's easy.
很简单
Just-
只要…
Just do what you do.
只要发挥你的本能
- It won't kill me。- What are you doing out here？You're supposed to be laying low.
- 它不肯杀我 - 你应该躲起来
I have one inside of me.
我体内也有一只
Big one won't kill its own.
大只的怪物不肯杀我
- What are you talking about？- I just saw it，
- 你在说什么？- 我刚刚看到了
an hour ago.
一小时前
I stood right next to it.
我就站在它旁边
I could've been lunch，but it wouldn't touch me.
它可以杀我 可是它不杀我
It ran away.
它跑掉了
It knows I'm carrying its future.
它知道我在孕育它的后代
Aw，bullshit。How do you know that thing's inside you？
胡说，你怎么知道你体内也有？
I saw it… on the CAT scan.
我透过断层扫描看到它
It's a queen-an egg layer.
它是个王后，会产卵
It can make thousands more like the one we've got here.
它会生出上千个这种怪物
Still sounds like bullshit to me.
听起来还是胡说八道
If that thing's inside you，how'd it get there？
那东西是怎么进入你体内？
I don't know.
不知道
When I was in hypersleep，I guess.
我在长眠的时候吧
l was violated.
它攻击我
Now I get to be the mother.
现在我成为王后之母
I don't have much time，
我的时间不多
and I can't do what I should.
无法做我该做的事
I need you to help me.
我要你帮忙
I need you to kill me.
你得杀死我
- What the fuck are you talking about？- I'm dead anyway.
- 你在胡说什么？- 反正我死定了
I can't survive it.
我活不了
But the one inside of me can generate thousands more，
我体内的异形会繁殖上千只后代
can wipe out the whole universe.
可以杀光整个宇宙
lt has to die.
它一定得死
So somebody's gotta kill me.
必须有人杀死我
Are you up to it？
你办得到吗？
You don't have to worry about that.
这点你不必担心
No speeches.
不必致词
No prayers.
也不必祷告
- What's going on？- I don't like losing a fight.
- 怎么回事？- 我不喜欢服输
Not to nobody，not to nothing.
对任何人或物都一样
Fuck。That damn thing out there has already killed half my men，
那东西杀死半数的弟兄
got the other half scared shitless.
另一半也被吓得半死
As long as it's alive，sister，you're not gonna save any universe.
只要它还活着，你就别想拯救宇宙
You said you were gonna kill me.
我叫你杀了我
- You fucking coward！- I want that thing！
- 你是胆小鬼 - 我要捉住它
I want to get this thing，and I need you to do it.
我要你帮我逮住它
And if it won't kill you，then maybe that helps us fight it.
它不肯杀你，也许对我们有利
Otherwise，fuck you！
不然就少说废话！
Go kill yourself.
你不帮忙就去死
Dillon.
迪伦
We waste this thing，
干掉这怪物之后
- then you take care of me。- No problem.
- 你就得除掉我 - 没问题
Quick，easy and painless.
你会死得痛快，不受折磨
This is the choice.
由你自己决定
You die sitting here on your ass，or you die out there.
你们想坐以待毙还是奋战到死
At least we take a shot。We owe it one.
至少我们该试试，让它好看
It's fucked us up。Maybe we can get even for the others.
它把我们都害惨了，应该来个以牙还牙
- Now how do you want it？- What the fuck are you talking about？
- 要怎么做？- 你在胡说什么？
I'm talkin' about killing that big motherfucker.
我是说去杀了那混帐东西
Hold it，hold it。The rescue team's on its way.
等一下，救援队要来了
We could just sit this out.
我们只要等就好了
- Rescue team for whom？- For us.
- 要救援谁呢？- 我们呀
They just want the beast。You know that.
他们只想要怪物
I don't give a damn what they want.
我才不管他们要什么
They're not gonna pick us off one by one，are they？
他们不会逐个接走吧？
I wouldn't be so sure.
这我不敢说
Come on。They're gonna take us home.
他们是来带我们回家的
They're not gonna take us home.
不是我们
Still doesn't mean we should go out and fight it.
我们不必跟它拼命
- Jesus Christ！Give us a break！- You guys have got to be fucking nuts！
- 天啊，饶了我们！- 你们都是笨蛋！
- Look，I've got a wife and a kid。- Nobody gives a shit about you，85.
- 我有老婆孩子 - 没有人睬你，85
You're not one of us。You're not a believer.
你不是我们的一员，你没有信仰
- You're a fucking company man！- Yeah，okay.
- 你只是个臭员工 - 好吧
Okay，I'm a company man and not a fucking criminal.
我是员工，不是臭囚犯
You keep telling me how dumb I am.
你一直骂我笨
Well，I'm smart enough not to have a life sentence on this rock！
起码我够聪明，不像你们永远被关在这里！
- Fuck you！- Piss off，85！
- 去你的头 - 滚开，85！
Yeah，and I'm smart enough to wait for some firepower to show up before we fight this thing！
我够聪明，我会等武器来了再上战场！
Right，Morse？
对吗，莫尔斯？
Right。Okay。Just sit here on your asses。Fine.
好吧，你就乖乖坐在这儿
How about if I sit here on my ass？
我也要乖乖坐在这里儿
No problem。Oh，I forgot.
没问题，我忘了
You're the guy that's made a deal with God…
你向上帝祈求…
to live forever，huh？
获得永生
And all the rest of you pussies can sit it out too.
其余的胆小鬼也可以坐着不动
Me and her'll do all the fighting.
我和她会负责打仗
Okay。But I want the same thing as you.
好吧，不过我要杀死它
I want to see it dead。I hate the fucker！It killed my mates too！
我恨透那东西，它也杀死我的好朋友
Why the fuck can't we wait for the company and have some guns on our side？
为何不等到公司把枪运来再动手？
- Why do we have to go on some fucking suicide run？- Right.
- 为何一定要白白送死？- 对
Because they won't kill it.
因为公司不会杀死它
They might kill you just for having seen it。But they're not gonna kill it.
他们可能杀了你们灭口
That is crazy！That is horseshit！They will not kill us！
太荒谬了，胡说八道，他们不会杀我们！
When they first heard about this thing，
当他们第一次听到有异形
it was 「crew expendable.」
就说可以牺牲船员
The next time they sent in marines。They were expendable too.
上次派去的海军陆战队也一样可以牺牲
What makes you think they're gonna care about a bunch of lifers…
难道他们会在乎…
who found God at the ass end of space？
关在外太空的囚犯吗？
You really think they're going to let you…
难道他们会让你们…
interfere with their plans for this thing？
破坏他们的计划吗？
They think we're-we're crud.
他们认为我们是垃圾
And they don't give a fuck about one friend of yours…
根本就不在乎你们的…
that's-that's died.
死活
Not one.
没有人在乎
Have you got some sort of plan？
你有计划吗？
This is a lead works，isn't it？
这是个铸铅厂，不是吗？
All we got to do is lure the fucking beast into the mold，
只要把异形丢进模子
drown it in hot lead.
让它溺死在滚烫的铅里
All right。So how do we do that？
好吧，我们该怎么做？
Yeah。What are we gonna use for bait？
没错，谁来当饵？
- Oh，fuck！- We're all gonna die.
- 该死 - 你们迟早都得死
The only question is when.
问题是怎样死法
This is as good a place as any…
这地方很适合…
to take your first steps to heaven.
做上天堂的第一步
Only question is how you check out.
问题只是要如何上去
Do you want it on your feet…
你们要死得轰轰烈烈…
or on your fucking knees，begging？
还是跪地求饶呢？
I ain't much for begging.
我不会求饶
Nobody ever gave me nothin'.
也没有人饶过我
So I say fuck that thing！Let's fight it！
我说干掉那怪物，跟他拼命
Fuck it！Let's go for it！
好吧，我们跟它拼了
- Let's kick its fucking ass。- What if it runs at us？
- 搞死它 - 它冲过来怎么办？
That's a fucking good idea.
最好先想出好办法来
Channel 「A，」 Door 1 open.
一号门开启
When was the last time you used this place？
你们几时用过这地方？
We fired it up five，six years ago.
五、六年前用过
You sure the piston's gonna work？
你确定活塞还能用？
There's nothing for sure in this place.
没有一样东西能确定
We trap it here first，then you pull the lever，start the piston.
它被困进去你就拉下把手，关起活塞
Then the piston's gonna push the mothersucker right into the mold.
把它推下模子，然后把铅倒进去
Then one of the guys will pour the lead。End of his ass。End of story.
很简单，它死定了
- What if somebody screws it up？- We're fucked。You got one chance.
- 要是有人搞砸呢？- 那就完蛋了，我们只有一次机会
One shot at it。That's all.
一击即中
We'll never have time to reset it。Now remember，when you pull the lever，
没时间重新再来，记住，当你拉下把手
for a few seconds you're gonna be trapped in here with that fuckin' thing.
你也会和那怪物困在里面一会儿
If you guys don't drop the ball，I won't.
你们不出差错，我也不会
Well，you just better be right about that thing not wanting you.
它最好真的不肯杀你
Because if it wants out，that's how it's gonna go.
它想逃出去只有一条路
Through that alcove，through you.
通过凹槽，通过你
- Where are you gonna be？- I'll be around.
- 你在哪里？- 我在附近
- What about the others？Where are they？- Praying.
- 其他人呢？- 在祷告
- You believe in this heaven shit？Eh？- I don't know.
- 你相信有天堂吗？- 不知道
Me neither.
我也是
Fuck it，though。What else have we got to believe in？
可恶，还有什么能相信呢？
Say that for fucking sure.
那就是事实
Well-Hey.
嘿
What the fuck，right？
去它的，对不？
Silence！I can't hear-
我听不到…
Let's launch this thing！
动作要迅速
Channel 「B，」 Door 7.
七号门关闭
I don't know about this shit.
情况不妙
- Hey，guys！My door ain't working！- What the fuck's he saying？
- 各位，我的门坏了 - 他在说什么？
I think we'd better rethink this thing！
我们最好重新考虑！
Did anybody hear anything？
有人听到声音吗？
Come on！Come and get me，you fucker！
来抓我呀，王八蛋！
It's behind me！
它在后面！
- It's starting。- Still behind me！
- 开始了 - 在后面！
It's in Channel 「B」！
它在B通道
Still coming！Shut the doors！
在后面，快关门！
Must be heading over to Channel 「A」！
它一定朝A通道去了
This thing is really pissed off！
这怪物真的发怒了
- Did you say 「B」？- No，「E」！
- 你刚刚说B吗？- 不，E
- But you said we should stay here！- Move your fucking ass！
- 你叫我留在这里 - 动作快点
Morse？
莫尔斯？
Kevin！
凯文！
I think I found Vincent！
找到文生了！
Yoo-hoo！Hey，fuckface！
丑八怪！
Come and get me！Take your best shot！
来抓我呀，快来呀，用力一点
Kevin，where are you？
凯文，你在哪里
A-7 closed.
A7关闭
Open the east wing。Door B-7 safe！
它在东厢，B7关闭！
- You cool？- Yeah！Okay。Over to 「E，」 everybody！
- 你也在这儿？- 大家都到E通道！
- Where the fuck is 「E」？- This way！
- E通道在哪里？- 这里
Troy。Troy？Troy，help 'em！
特洛伊？特洛伊？好，快追
How did I get here？
怎样过来？
Where the hell are they going？What about the plan？
他们去哪里？怎么不照计划？
- Look，you're immune，they're not。- So what are we doing？
- 你免疫了，他们可没有 - 那该怎么办？
- Improvising！- We're improvising.
- 随机应变！- 随机应变
Great.
这下好了
Here。Here，kitty，kitty，kitty.
过来！猫咪！过来！
Here，kitty，kitty.
过来！猫咪！猫咪！
Oh，my God.
我的天！
Oh，my-You bastard！
你这畜牲
It's coming！It's coming，Dillon！Geez，it's coming！
它过来了，从隧道过来 ！
It's comin' after us！Shut the fucking doors！That was the plan！
它盯上我们了，照计划把门关上！
Geez，it's on the fucking ceiling！
天哪，在上面！
Dillon！Anybody！This is not a drill！
迪伦，来人呀，这不是演习
Kevin！Gregor！
凯文、格雷戈尔
Where the fuck are you？
你们在哪里？
Now I'm back in 「A」！
我们又回到A通道
Shut。Come on.
快关上
Door 3，「F」 Channel closed！
第3道门，F通道已关闭！
I hope.
希望是
Fuck！
操！
What the fuck are you doing？What？
你在干什么？
Don't hold it like that。Hold it like this。What the fuck-
别那样拿，这样拿
You'll fucking kill someone，you fucking moron！Ow！
你会刺死人，蠢蛋
Morse！Kevin！
莫尔斯、凯文
Gregor！
格雷戈尔
All they have to do is run down the damn corridor.
他们只要跑过通道就行
Stay here.
留在这里
Where the hell is it？
它到底在哪里？
It's coming。Aw，Jesus！
来了，老天，在那里
No！Don't start the piston！
不要打开活塞！
No！We have to trap it！No！
我们得先困住它！
No！What are you doing？It's gone！No！No.
你在干嘛？它跑掉了
It's gone.
它跑掉了
Okay？
好吗？
Okay.
好的
What the heck？
什么鬼东西？
All right！
好的！
Kevin！Don't struggle！
凯文，不要挣扎
Don't move！No！Don't struggle！
别动，不要挣扎
Come on。Come on，Kevin。Come on！
来呀！来呀！凯文！来呀！
Come on！Come on！Come on.
来呀！来呀！来呀！
- The doors。- It's coming！
- 关门！- 它来了！
Take the piston！
准备活塞！
I got ya。It's all right.
好了！没事了！
It's okay。I got ya。It's okay.
It's all right，Kevin.
没事了，凯文！
Kevin！
凯文！
Kevin.
Leave him.
把他放下
Leave him。He's dead。Lure it in.
把他放下，他死了，引它进来
Shit。How much time？
可恶，还要多久？
I'm not sure。Four or five minutes.
不确定，四、五分钟
But we've got to get it back in here before the piston seals this place off.
我们得在活塞封闭之前把它引回这里
Now，let's move it！
快行动！
- Help me！- Jude！
- 救命！- 朱德！
Dillon！Help me，Dillon！
迪伦！救命！迪伦！
It's coming at me！
它在追我！
Don't look back，Jude！Run as fast as you fucking can！
别往后看，赶快跑！
Help me！
迪伦！救我！
God！Please！Help！
迪伦！救我！拜托！
Channel 「C，」 Door 3 closed.
C通道，三号门关闭
Jesus Christ！Thank God you're here.
谢天谢地，你们终于来了
Warder Aaron，sir。1-3-7-5-1-2.
狱吏亚伦，长官，137512
- Not many of us left，sir。- Where is Lieutenant Ripley？
- 幸存的人不多 - 蕾普莉中尉呢？
- Is she still alive？- If she's alive，she's in the furnace.
- 她还活着吗？- 她还活着，就在熔炉那里
She's in the lead works with the beast.
她和怪物在铸铅厂
Wouldn't wait.
她不肯等你们
- Jesus Christ。- You fucker。Scared me shitless！
- 老天 - 你这浑蛋把我吓得半死！
I thought you were the fucking beast。You fuck！
我以为你是那怪物，大笨蛋！
Wanker！
笨蛋！
Move。Come on，you bastard！
来呀！你这畜牲！
Come on！Come on，get out of there！
来呀！来呀！离开这里！
Come here！
过来！
Ripley，we're running out of time！
蕾普莉！时间无多！
Ripley，where are you？
蕾普莉！你在哪里？
No！
不！
I'm over here
上面！我在上面！
Come on。Get out of there！
来呀！过来！
What the fuck is wrong with you？No！No！
你在干嘛？你有病吗？
Let it go！Let it go！
放过它！放过它！
- Yes！It's working！- Scream！
- 好！成功了！到活塞！- 快尖叫！
- To the piston！- Scream！Let it follow us.
- 到活塞！- 快尖叫！让它跟来
Come on！We got to get it in front of the piston.
把它引到活塞前
Get back there。It's following us！
回来！跟上来了！
Motherfucker！Come on！Come and get us！
过来！你这怪物
Come on！
过来！
Up to the door！Close it！
到门边！
Come on，motherfucker！Come on.
来呀！混蛋！来呀！
Come on！Get the door！
快点！把门关上！
- Get the door！- Morse！
- 把门关上！- 莫尔斯！
Now！Shut it！
快关门！
Shut it，Morse！
莫尔斯，把门关上！
Morse，shut that door！
- Now！- Shut the fucking door！
- 快点！- 把门关上！
I'm going for the lead！
我去倒热铅
- Go！Now！- What about you？
- 现在 - 你呢？
- I'm staying。- Bullshit！There's gonna be 10 tons of hot lead in there！
- 我要留下 - 这里会灌进十顿热铅
- I keep telling you，I want to die！- We got a deal！
- 我说过，我想死 - 我们说好了
Remember？It dies first，then you！
记得吗？它先死，然后才是你
I'm not gonna move without you！Now get going！
你不走我也不走，快走吧
- Dillon！- I've got to hold it here.
- 迪伦 - 我在这儿挡住它
- What about me？- God will take care of you now，sister！
- 那我呢？- 上帝会照顾你，妹子
No！
不！
Pour the lead.
把热铅倒下来
Fuck you.
去你的
Go on！Pour it，Ripley！Go on！Damn it！
快倒！蕾普莉！快呀！
Pour that lead，Ripley！Pour it now！
把铅倒下来，蕾普莉，快点！
Come on！Come on！That's all you've got？
来啊！你只有这点能耐？
Is that all that you fight，motherfucker！Come on！
你只有这点能耐？来呀！浑蛋！快点！倒呀！
Morse！Morse，over here！
莫尔斯！这里！
- Ripley！- Pour the lead！
- 蕾普莉 - 把铅倒下去！
Pour the lead！
把铅倒下去
Pour it！
倒下去
I hate bugs！
最讨厌虫子了！
Ripley！It's burning hot！
蕾普莉，它热得滚烫！
Hit the sprinklers！
打开洒水器！
Douse the fucker！
淋死这王八蛋！
Gotcha！
干掉你了
Yes！
好极了！
- Don't come any closer。- Wait。They're here to help.
- 不要再过来 - 等等，他们是来帮忙
Stay where you are！
别过来
- Ripley。- Bishop.
- 蕾普莉 - 主教
- I'm here to help you。- No more bullshit.
- 我是来帮助你的 - 别再骗我了
I just felt it move.
它在我体内蠕动
- You know who I am？- You're a droid.
- 你知道我是谁吗？- 你是个生化人
Same model as Bishop。Sent by the fucking company.
与主教同型号，公司派来的
No。I'm not the Bishop android.
我不是主教那种生化人
I designed it.
他是我设计的
I'm very human.
我是人类
The company sent me here to show you a friendly face，
公司派个熟悉面孔来找你
to demonstrate how important you are to us，
表示你有多重要
to me.
对我也是
- You just want to take it back。- We want to kill it and take you home.
- 你只想把它带回去 - 我们要杀了它，带你回家
- Bullshit。- You're wrong。We want to help.
- 才怪 - 你错了，我们想帮你
What does that mean？
什么意思？
- We're gonna take that out of you。- And keep it.
- 我们会替你取出它 - 然后留它活口
Can't allow it to live。Everything we know would be in jeopardy.
我们不能让它活着，否则人类将面临危机
You don't want to take it back？
你不想把它带回去？
Ripley，time is important。Let us deal with the malignancy.
蕾普莉，时间不多，我们要赶快解决这个恶魔
We've got a surgical bay set up on the rescue ship.
救援舰有手术台
Come with me。It's very quick.
跟我来吧，手术快速
Painless。A couple of incisions。You'll be out for two hours.
无痛，只要几刀，两小时就好了
And then it's over.
一切就结束了
You still can have a life，children-
你还能过正常生活，生儿育女
And most important，you'll know it's dead.
最重要的，你会知道它真正死了
Let me help you.
让我帮你吧
What guarantee do I have…
我怎样肯定…
once you've taken it out，you'll destroy it？
你们把它取出来，就会消灭它？
You have to trust me.
你得相信我
Please？Trust me？
求你相信我
No.
不
What's this gonna achieve？
这样有什么用？
- Stop！- Ow！Oh，Jesus！
- 住手！- 老天！
Morse.
莫尔斯！
- Will you help me？- What do you want me to do？
- 你愿意帮助我吗？- 你要我做什么？
It was a mistake！There was no need for any of it！
这是个误会，你们不该伤人
Fucking android！
可恶的生化人
I'm not a droid！
我不是生化人
Ripley，think of all we could learn from it.
蕾普莉，想想能从它身上学到的
It's the chance of a lifetime！
这是毕生难逢的机会
You must let me have it！It's a magnificent specimen！
你得让我留下它，它是个优秀生物！
Oh，Jesus！
天啊！
No pictures！
不要拍摄！
You're crazy.
你疯了
What are you doing？
你要做什么？
No！
不！
- Come on，you。Get going。- Oh，fuck you！
- 快点！快点走！- 去你的！
Ash，Captain Dallas are dead.
艾许和达拉斯船长都死了
Cargo and ship destroyed.
货物和船全部被毁
I should reach the frontier in about six weeks.
我在六周后将抵达边界
With a little luck，the network will pick me up.
幸运的话，有人会来拯救
This is Ripley，
我是蕾普莉
last survivor of the Nostromo，signing off.
诺斯托罗莫号唯一生还者，报告完毕
（「复仇」161星球 劳动监狱关闭封锁）
（监管驻防事务终止）
（存留铸炼设备 当废铁出售）
（传讯完毕）